# **Anirudh Sylendranath**

## Senior Software Engineer

https://github.com/aniforprez https://www.linkedin.com/in/anirudh-sylendranath/

## **Summary**

Senior software engineer with 12+ years of experience in software engineering with a focus on web application design and development and improving developer experience using open source tools. Worked on numerous production cloud SaaS applications and products on the frontend and the backend in multiple horizontals including finance, campaigning, marketing etc.

#### Skills

**Programming Languages:** Python, NodeJS, Golang, Ruby **Frameworks:** Django, Flask, Express, NextJS, React, Rails

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**Technologies:** AWS, Docker, Kubernetes

## **Experience**

**Freelance** | Freelance Programmer and Interview Engineer

Sep, 2023 — Current

- Worked as a solo developer and founder on finesse.money, a personal finance manager that is currently still in development. It was built with Go, JS, React Router and Tailwind
- Worked as an Interview Engineer for Karat, interviewing candidates for programming roles and providing structured feedback to clients
- Worked on various small programming projects for various clients in Python and Flutter (using Flutter Flow)

#### **Synup Digital** | Senior Software Engineer

Jun, 2021 — Aug, 2023

- Designing, architecting and developing new customer facing features such as a real-time integration with Google Business Messaging to allow clients to communicate with customers
- Worked on a microservices driven backend with services written in multiple languages like Python (Django, Flask), Ruby (Rails), NodeJS using multiple databases such as Postgres, Amazon RDS using queues driven by Kafka, Redis, RabbitMQ
- Worked on improvements to a monolithic React frontend as well as building smaller NextJS based bespoke microapps for client requirements
- Leading efforts to improve developer experience and raise code quality standards using language upgrades, linting, formatting, CI/CD checks
- Mentoring, leading and guiding junior developers across projects

#### eSthenos Technologies | Technical Lead (Promoted)

Sep, 2020 — May, 2021

 Developed a unified external services platform for company-wide use integrating with third-party SMS, Credit reporting and Money transfer services

- Leading efforts to upgrade older apps to modern standards using new dependency tools, 12-factor practices, containerization, deploying on AWS Fargate
- Developed internal tools easing developer experience such as a PDF previewer for frontend developers
- Mentoring, leading and guiding junior developers across projects

#### eSthenos Technologies | Senior Python Developer

Dec, 2018 — Aug, 2020

- Owned client projects and lead teams contributing to new features, updates and bug fixes
- Planned processes to convert projects from Python 2 to 3 and updated multiple projects
- Built integrations to Credit reporting, Money transfer and client CRM services for projects
- Setup CI pipelines in Bitbucket to automate code health checks, tests and deployments

#### Canopy (Mesitis) | Contract Full Stack Developer

Mar, 2017 — Feb, 2018

- Developed an API and frontend system to generate PPT files for financial presentations
- Developed Python Analytics APIs that performed analytics from existing financial data
- Rapid prototyping of various new frontend data displays for different datasets for clients

#### CallHub.io | Full Stack Developer

Aug, 2015 — Feb, 2017

- Developed a frontend UI in AngularJS including UI/UX design and API development in Django for a real-time Call Center solution using Twilio and Plivo WebRTC APIs
- Developed a custom build system for Angular using Gulp supporting translations for any languages
- Worked with analytics team to develop a frontend for data points generated from Apache Spark analytics

#### House of Blue Beans | Web Developer

Nov, 2014 — Aug, 2015

- Developed Blender Python scripts to import models from an online scene builder to be used to make realistic renders in Blender for clients like Urban Ladder
- Developed a custom CMS admin panel in AngularJS to manage a database of 3D models online for a client
- Rewrote numerous Flash kids' educational games in Javascript using the Phaser framework
- Developed and managed company website

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions | Programmer Analyst

Feb, 2013 — Aug, 2014

- Bug squashing of COBOL code on Remote Mainframe Systems
- Instrumental in efforts to convert existing JCL project to to Java/Hadoop

### **Education**

#### **Amrita School of Engineering**

Jan, 2008 — Jan, 2013

B.Tech - Computer Science and Engineering